Richard Petrow Papers
Richard Petrow Papers
1963-1969
Petrow, Richard.
2.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American author. Collection includes correspondence, notes, galley proofs, and research material relating to his books Across the Top of Russia and The Black Tide.
149470
Biographical History
Richard Petrow was an American author. Much of his writing focused on some aspect of marine stewardship, including shrimping, boating, arctic seas, and oil spills.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Richard Petrow Papers consists of correspondence and writings. The majority of the collection is research notes for his book The Black Tide, which deals with the 1967 wreck of the tanker Torrey Canyon and the ensuing oil spill on the coasts of Cornwall (England) and Brittany (France).
The collection begins with a small amount of Correspondence. Writings includes notes, galleys, proofs, and research material relating to articles, books, and scripts written by Petrow. The majority concerns The Black Tide, but there is also material from his book Across the Top of Russia, about the cruise of the U.S. Coast Guard ship Northwind into the polar seas north of Siberia.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Writings are arranged alphabetically by type and within that by title of work.
Subject and Genre Headings
Science and medicine; Activism and social reform; Petrow, Richard -- Archives.; Petrow, Richard. Across the top of Russia.; Petrow, Richard. Black tide.; Torrey Canyon (Ship); Authors, American.; Oil spills, Environmental aspects.; Correspondence.; Galley proofs.; Authors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - David McKay Company, Inc., 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Northwind [Coast Guard ship], 1965 (Box 1)
  - Reader's Digest, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Eight boating crises", 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - "Florida's newest boom industry: cattle rustling", 1967-1969 (Box 1)
    - "Government scientists keep shrimp hopping", 1963-1968 (Box 1)
    - "Those wonderful fish that no one wants", 1968 (Box 1)
    - "Unraveling secret signals of the animal world", 1968 (Box 1)
    - "The World Glory disaster", 1968 (Box 1)
  - Books
    - Across the top of Russia
      - Editing material, 1966 (Box 1)
      - Galleys, 1967 (Box 1)
      - Page proofs, 1967 (Box 1)
      - Research material
        - Biographies, 1965 (Box 1)
        - Notes, 1965 (Box 1)
    - The Black Tide
      - Research material
        - Birds, 1967; 2 folders (Box 1)
        - Bombing, 1967 (Box 1)
        - British government (official), 1967 (Box 1)
        - British Petroleum, 1967 (Box 1)
        - Coast guard, 1967 (Box 1)
        - Cornwall (character), circa 1967 (Box 1)
        - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
        - Cost, 1967 (Box 1)
        - Detergents and booms, 1967 (Box 1)
        - Effect of oil outside of Cornwall (in England), 1967 (Box 1)
        - Effect on other countries, 1967 (Box 1)
        - First sighting, 1967 (Box 1)
        - Flags of convenience, 1967 (Box 1)
        - France
          - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 1)
          - General articles, 1967 (Box 1)
          - News clippings and chronological messages, 1967 (Box 1)
          - Scientific, 1967 (Box 1)
          - Tourism, 1967 (Box 1)
        - French beaches, 1967 (Box 1)
        - French crabbers, 1967 (Box 1)
        - French fish and birds, 1967 (Box 1)
        - General articles, 1967 (Box 1)
        - Grounding, 1967 (Box 1)
        - Insurance, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Intergovernmental Maritime Consultative Organization (IMCO), 1967 (Box 2)
        - Italian crew, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Lawsuit, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Liberian inquiry, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
        - Local authorities, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Marine life, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
        - Military operations, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Navy, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Oil pollution
          - General, 1967 (Box 2)
          - Before Torrey Canyon, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
          - Early days, 1967 (Box 2)
          - Middle, 1967 (Box 2)
          - Aftermath, 1967 (Box 2)
          - Tankers other than Torrey Canyon, 1967 (Box 2)
          - World War II tankers, 1967 (Box 2)
          - Profit from, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Oil slick, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Photographs, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Political implications, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Porthleven, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Press comments, cartoons, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Preventative action (future), 1967 (Box 2)
        - Rescue, 1967 (Box 2)
        - Rugiati, Captain Pastrengo, 1967 (Box 2)
        - St. Ives, 1967 (Box 3)
        - Salvage, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
        - Scientific aspects, 1963-1968 (Box 3)
        - Tankers, 1967 (Box 3)
        - Testimonies, 1967 (Box 3)
        - Torrey Canyon, 1967 (Box 3)
        - Tourist problem, 1967 (Box 3)
        - Typescript notes, undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
        - United States reaction to Torrey Canyon, 1967 (Box 3)
      - Uncorrected proof, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Scripts
    - CBS Radio, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
    - CBS Television, "One of a kind: the reconstruction", 1964 (Box 3)